Francisco Alfonso **Mayorga Cetina**

Mathematician - Software Developer

Professional in mathematics with ease and disposition for learning. I have more than two years of experience using object oriented programming (.NET) and data analysis (Python, R) tools.

I am interested in software development, scientific research and mathematical teaching, as well as digital design and illustration.



in francisco-mayorga-cetina

Adobe suite

C#

F#

IPF

Java LaTex

R

SQL

Moodle

OBS Studio Python

Sagemath

Godot English [B2]

Tools and abilities

Education

Mathematics

Sergio Arboleda University, January 2014 - May 2020 Thesis: Characterizing Dual Graphs Associated to Triangulations of the Caracol Flow Polytope

Learn Python & Ethical hacking from scratch, Udemy, February 2020

Python Cetification Course, Programming Hub, August 2020

Python 3 Cetification Course, Programming Hub, August 2020

Python Advanced Cetification Course, Programming Hub, August 2020

UI/UX Certification Course, Programming Hub, November 2021

Experience

Development Analyst

Finac S.A.S., November 2020 - Currently

Analysis, estimation, design and implementation of software development solutions for company applications

Team coordinator at "Monitores Sergistas"

Sergio Arboleda University, June 2018 - January 2020

Selection process for new candidates, evaluation and six-monthly statistical analysis of team's performance. Management of administrative and logistical processes, etc.

Volunteer

HAIKO foundation, February 2019 - November 2020

Teaching support in Discrete Mathematics and Computational Thinking courses

Publications

A unifying framework for the v-Tamari lattice and principal order ideals in Young's lattice Combinatorica Magazine (in review process), Springer editorial, February 2021

On framed triangulations of flow polytopes, the v-Tamari lattice and Young's lattice

Proceedings of the 33rd International Conference on "Formal Power Series and Algebraic Combinatorics", Séminaire Lotharingien de Combinatoire - FPSAC 2021, Bar Ilan University, Ramat Gan, Israel. April 2021

References

Marta Yaneth Corzo Gómez

Mathematics school dear Sergio Arboleda University

Rafael S. Gonzalez D'León

Researcher teacher Pontifical Xaverian University

Leidy Alicia Tinjacá Romero

Sergio Arboleda University

Activities and events

XX Congreso Colombiano de Matemáticas

Attendee, National University of Colombia, Manizales, July 2015

Maratón nacional de programación ICPC

Contestant, Politécnico Grancolombiano; 2015, 2016, 2017, 2018 y 2019

Cube Challenge Sergista

Organizer, Sergio Arboleda University, 2018 y 2019

XXII Congreso Colombiano de Matemáticas

Speaker, University of Cauca, Popayán, June 2019 Poster: Flow polytopes and triangulations of the Caracol polytope

Maratón Regional de Programación (South America North) ICPC

Contestant, Politécnico Grancolombiano, November 2019